Singer. Activist. Survivor. Legend.
Nina is a drama, music film directed by Cynthia Mort.
The story of the late jazz musician and classical pianist Nina Simone including her
rise to fame and relationship with her manager Clifton Henderson.
Nina Simone, played by Zoe Saldaña.
Clifton Henderson, played by David Oyelowo.
Richard Pryor, played by Mike Epps.
Lorraine Hansberry, played by Ella Thomas.
Henri Edwards, played by Ronald Guttman.
Clifton's Mom, played by Ella Joyce.
Nina is a 2016 American biographical film written and directed by Cynthia Mort.
The film focuses on American musician and civil rights
activist Nina Simone, portrayed by Zoe Saldaña.
The film also stars David Oyelowo, Ella Thomas, and Mike Epps.
It had a limited release beginning April 22, 2016, and
through video on demand by RLJ Entertainment.
The film received strong criticism, including the casting of Saldaña in
the lead, and Simone's family refused to endorse it.
Saldaña later said she regretted accepting the lead role.
The film explores themes of jazz, biography,
based on true story, woman director.
The tone is emotional.